ADEBAYO ADEOLA

Halifax, NS | B3S 1J8 | https://bayoadeola.cyclic.app | 782-414-0745 | bayocana@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/adebayo-adeola

PROFILE

Data Analyst with more than 5 years experience in Power BI, Python, SQL, sales, banking operations, business intelligence and software development. A dedicated professional with training in Business Intelligence and Analytics with strong analytical and problem-solving abilities. I also possess diverse technical skills necessary to collaborate with various departments and explaining complex concepts to non-technical stakeholders.

SKILLS

- **Business Analysis:** Business requirements gathering, elicitation & documentation, use cases and documenting business processes
- Business Intelligence: Power BI, Power Query, DAX, Python, Tableau, MS Excel
- Database Development: PLSQL/T-SQL: functions, stored procedures, MS SQL Server, Mongo DB, SSIS, SSRS
- Cloud Computing: Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services
- Agile/SCRUM: Git, GitHub, Jira, Jenkins
- **Application Development:** debugging and testing experience, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, React Native, Electron, Expo
- Operating Systems: Linux, Mac, Bash scripting, DOS

Soft Skills: Excellent written and verbal communication skills. Strong interpersonal relationship skills. A continuous and willing learner as shown in my academic trainings and certifications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analytst, Teaching Assistant Skills for Hire, Digital Nova Scotia

06/2023 - Date

- Training on Python for Data Analysis to alter CSV files or Excel spreadsheets, ransposing and pivoting data
- Teaching hands-on Data Visualization and Data Reporting with PowerBI reporting and Tableau
- Teaching Data Modeling: Implementing database models with DAX (Data Analysis Expressions)
- Tutoring Machine Learning; Natural Language Processing with Python
- Tutoring cloud technologies and services Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Relational Database Management training and Data Quality Management with MS SQL Server.

Data Analyst (Volunteer)

Data for Good Maritimes, Halifax, Nova Scotia

05/2023 - Date

- Understanding business data and maintaining the integrity and quality of the data
- Data Analysis, Data Profiling and Interpretation: Analyze raw data, manipulate data sets, and interpret results to provide insightful, data-driven business solutions.
- Using SQL queries, Power Query, DAX and PowerBI to ascertain data quality, perform data migration and integration
- Business documentations and readme files for data manipulation and visualization
- Using Slack as a collaborative tool to share files and communicate
- Designing , Developing and Maintaining BI Solutions: Developing data analytics platforms; dashboards, reports, and metrics using Microsoft Power BI.
- Data Integration: Connect multiple data sources, integrating them into a unified, understandable dataset. Implement row-level security on data and have an understanding of application security layer models in Power BI.

Peer Assisted Learning Support

02/2022 - 04/2023

Nova Scotia Community College, IT Campus, Halifax, Nova Scotia.

- Taught JavaScript, Python, Business Intellience & Analytics and Structured Query Language
- Taught designing, Developing and Maintaining BI Solutions: Developing data analytics platforms; dashboards, reports, and metrics using Microsoft Power BI and Microsoft SSRS.
- Taught Data Integration: Connect multiple data sources including time series and other datasets; CSV and other text

files, spreadsheets and various data files, integrating them into a unified, understandable dataset. Implement row-level security on data and have an understanding of application security layer models in Power BI.

• Teaching data warehouse concepts; ETL processes with integration tools; SSIS and MS SQL Server.

Summer Scholarship Awardee

Research Nova Scotia

04/2023 - 06/2023

- Created a Mobile App PracticeHealthNS
- Used Google Firestore and Google Authentication back-end
- Used React-Native framework and libraries to design front-end

Collaborator, Exchanges and Returns

08/2022 - Date

IKEA, Halifax, Nova Scotia.

- Customer service that is committed, responsive, articulate, reliable and responsive
- Actively listen to customers and discover their needs, process transactions in accordance with IKEA's policies
- Collaborates with team members through Sharepoint and teams to meet service goals

Relationship Manager

01/2018 - 08/2021

Zenith Bank PLC, a global Financial Institution with head-office in Nigeria.

www.zenithbank.com

Business Strategy: Achieved 75 % of sales target by developing and integrating targeted online and offline lead generation programs

Business Development: Mobilized deposits and sold various bank's products and services

Leadership: Co-ordinated and managed a team of 6 Relationship Managers

Relationship Management: Identified, established and developed relationship with individuals and companies Business Intelligence and Analytics: Used Power Query (MS Excel) to visualize branch's clients performance against previous months, quarters and years, generated SQL Scripts (Stored Procedures) to retrieve trends in customers' transactions profiles

Financial Advisory: provided financial advisory services to customers with integrity and innovation

EDUCATION

2023
2022
2011
2010
2023

Training, mentorship and networking to understand the diverse culture of the workplace and business

ISANS - Immigration Services Association of Nova Scotia (Client) 05/2023

Understanding workplace culture, diversity, equity and inclusion. Career workshops

CERTIFICATIONS

Fundamentals of Agile Project Management **03/2023** Microsoft Certified: **Azure** Fundamentals **07/2022**

Microsoft Certified: Power Platform Fundamentals 07/2022

Microsoft Certified: AI Fundamentals 08/2022

Microsoft Office User Specialist (MOUS, Microsoft Excel) 12/2018.

Project Management Professional(PMP) 07/2017